# Aubry Lungu

### Education and Training

Master of Science, Data Science, Expected in 08/2024 University of East London, London

Bachelor of Science, in Computer Science, 11/2017

Mulungushi University, Kabwe

#### Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://aubrylungu.vercel.app/
- https://github.com/aubryll

#### Summary

Experienced engineer with over 5 years of experience in user interface/user experience design, data analysis, and the design and development of digital products. I am interested in a position that will put my talents and experience to good use while also providing me with opportunities to learn and grow.

#### Experience

#### FRONT END UX/UI ENGINEER 01/2022 - Current

Orbis International, New York, USA

Conducted generative research to understand the needs and potential feature sets of new digital products for a variety of clients

Conducted evaluative research to test the usability and usefulness of current digital products Presented research findings to teams and stakeholders to inform product strategy and design Created surveys, test concepts, and conducted in-person and remote 1:1 user interviews Advocated for diversity and inclusion in user research, with specific experience in accessibility

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - CONSULTANT 02/2021 - 06/2022

Open energy labs, London, United Kingdom

Led the user research process for a variety of digital products, including mobile apps and websites Conducted generative and evaluative research using a range of methods such as surveys, usability testing, and in-depth interviews

Presented research findings to teams and stakeholders to inform product strategy and design Created and administered surveys to gather insights on user needs and preferences Worked with designers to incorporate research findings into product development

PRODUCT DEVELOPER 03/2020 - 03/2021
FIRST QUANTUM MINERALS LIMITED, Solwezi, Zambia

Spearheaded product development from initial design conceptualization to manufacturing and final delivery to clients.

Facilitated quality assurance and product assessments to promote high-quality productions.

Researched modern product trends and adapted designs to match.

Prepared sketches and detailed drawings of designs and projected product ideas.

#### PROJECT MANAGER - CONSULTANT 08/2018 - 08/2019

AB BANK ZAMBIA, Lusaka, Zambia

Developed project plans that included objectives, resources needed, and timelines.

Project staff work was coordinated, including task assignment and performance monitoring.

Delivered projects on schedule, under budget, and with high quality standards.

By offering excellent program leadership, I was able to enhance development and drive continuous improvement in the project delivery process.

## **SYSTEM ANALYST - VOLUNTEER** 11/2017 - 08/2018

WESBR FOUNDATION, Lusaka, Zambia

Developed and monitored project plans while providing management with progress reports.

Designed a simplified task system to allow more efficient workflows for both peers and management personnel.

When directing project teams, I maintained quality-focused performance benchmarks and schedules. Investigated new technologies and tools for productivity, security, and quality assurance.

## **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER** 07/2017 - 12/2017 **CRYSTALINE TECHNOLOGIES**, Lusaka, Zambia

Scrum and Kanban approaches were streamlined into the development processes to standardize and speed operations.

Integrated cutting-edge development approaches to reduce turnaround times and increase client loyalty. JUnit, Jasmine, and Selenium were used to automate diagnostic testing of produced applications.

#### Skills

- UI/UX
- Data management
- Data analysis
- Project management
- Mobile development
- React & React Native
- Java, Kotlin & C#
- Typescript & Javascript
- SQL & Python
- Training & development
- Testing & deployment